# **Alexandre Paes**



alexpaes.itsolutions@gmail.com



linkedin.com/in/alexandre-paes



https://github.com/LondonComputadores

### Summary

Hi! I'm Alexandre Paes but you can call me Alex if you prefer. I am 38 years old and 3 years ago I started my transition from 8 years in Network Infrastructure to Software Development. Five brief contacts with programming, the first in 2001 with Delphi and in 2013 with PHP, Java and Javascript Vanilla. In 2017 I came back to stay and started with Python through Data Science and Analysis with data extraction and manipulation from datalakes and SQL database and using excel spreadsheets to clean the data. 2018 I decided to expand my knowledge and advanced to Web Development, with Python Django Flask, React Angular Vue Node.js, REST API, Microservices, Messaging with RabbitMQ, making use of Dockers containers and simple configuration of kubernetes to orchestrate the clusters. I participated in challenges, hackatons and even selective items in addition to opportunities for python, such as Ruby on Rails, Golang, C # .Net and Java Spring. In the last month of October, now at the end of 2020, I graduated in Systems Analysis and Development at Estácio de Sá in Rio de Janeiro, where I lived for 4 years. I also lived in London, England, for 7 years, which gave me, in addition to international experience, a good and advanced English spoken skil.

Spoken English level: Advanced (7 years lived in London, England, UK)

Objectives: Even knowing that I'm able to get a Mid Developer job, I'd love to get a junior or a junior/mid or maximum a mid 1, when mid 3 is the most experienced, python back-end or python django back-end or a python django react.js/vue.js full stack developer role! I'm qualifying myself to be a DevSecOps in the future, so meanwhile I'd like to learn more about it as a developer and perhaps be able to contribute to the projects I'm working on! Data Science and Analysis have been put aside but never abandoned. REST API and a bit of micro services has been the main topic that every single project without distinguish of technology used, so I'm putting a lot of effort on it to get better and better.

### **Experience**



#### xogito Python Developer

Xogito Group, Inc.

May 2021 - Sep 2021 (5 months)

Python Flask back-end developer: Responsible for developing the REST API's for a large application called CMMC (Standard for Cyber Security Training), using also PostgreSQL, SQLAlchemy, Marshmellow, Alembic and Swagger.



#### Junior/Mid Python Django React.js Full Stack Developer

Sponsor Analytytics Inc.

Nov 2020 - Apr 2021 (6 months)

Python Django: Developing the whole back-end with django, graphene, fastapi, postgresql, terraform and aws

React.js/ Node.js: Doing code reviews and debugging and also the integration with the back-end and deploy to production via aws lambda and terraform to aws



**Analista Desenvolvedor** 

#### London Computadores - Autônomo - Self-employed

Jan 2011 - Mar 2021 (10 years 3 months)

projects as an independent contractor self- employed/freelancer. Working mostly with computer networking, help desk and hardware maintenance, and also with php and wordpress websites occasionally

#### **Education**



### **Estácio**

Tecnólogo em Análise e Desenvolvimento de Sistemas, Information Technology 2018 - 2020

# 💮 In

#### Instituto Infnet

Computer Network Technologist - Tecnologia em Redes de Computadores (3 years course), Information Technology

2017 - 2020

Computer Network Degree with 8 international certifications including MCSA, CCNA, CEH, PMP, etc...

- Graduação em Redes de Computadores com 8 certificações internacionais incluindo MCSA, CCNA, CEH, PMP, etc...

# **Udacity Brasil**

Nanodegree Foundation Data Science I, Computer and Information Sciences and Support Services

2017 - 2018

Python Data Science with Anaconda, Numpy, Pandas, Matplot, Jupyter Notebook, Git, HTML, Linux & Windows

# Anhanguera Uniderp

Tecnico em Redes de Computadores (PRONATEC), Redes de Computadores 2014 - 2016

Computer Network Technician

### Treinatec

Técnico, Web/Multimedia Management and Webmaster

2013 - 2013

Webmaster - Full Stack Development

#### **Licenses & Certifications**



#### Computer Network Technician (Técnico em Redes de Computadores - Pronatec)

- PRONATEC Anhanguera

#### **MCPS: Microsoft Certified Professional** - Microsoft

- **Web Developer & Web Designer** Treinatec Web Master
- Nanodegree Foundation Data Science I
- Bertelsmann Data Science Challenge Scholarship Udacity
- **SMS Expert Comtele** Digital Innovation One Inc. F86E6D7F
- Projetos ágeis com SCRUM Digital Innovation One Inc. 9FDE3DBF
- Programação para internet com JavaScript Digital Innovation One Inc. EBE26FE2
- Introdução à programação com Python Digital Innovation One Inc. 2965BFFC
- Desenvolvimento para Internet e Banco de Dados com Python e Django Digital Innovation One Inc. AD479456
- Introdução à biblioteca jQuery Digital Innovation One Inc. 6A779AE6
- Introdução ao Node.js com Express Digital Innovation One Inc. 06B1DA47
- Desenvolvimento Avançado Python com Flask e REST API Digital Innovation One Inc. 0681C85A
- Desenvolvimento Avançado com JavaScript ES6 Digital Innovation One Inc. E85D51EC
- Construindo páginas para internet com Bootstrap Digital Innovation One Inc. EC4703E5
- GFT START\_UNI Digital Innovation One Inc.

Desenvolvimento de aplicações para internet com ReactJS - Digital Innovation One Inc. 2B4020A2

Desenvolvedor Web Front-End - Digital Innovation One Inc. F4215716

Talentos ReactJS 2020 - Digital Innovation One Inc. 33ACFECF

Talentos ReactJS 2020 - Digital Innovation One Inc. 33ACFECF

- Entendendo Promises De Uma Vez Por Todas Digital Innovation One Inc. 4414730E
- PostgreSQL Conceitos e Melhores Práticas Digital Innovation One Inc. 73B5DDB3
- Desenvolvimento back-end com Node.js Digital Innovation One Inc. A1F28D34
- Desenvolvedor Web Back-End Digital Innovation One Inc. 04E8CAED
- **Desenvolvedor Web FULL STACK** Digital Innovation One Inc. EF309819
- Primeiros passos com .Net + C# Digital Innovation One Inc. C45CD626
- Desenvolvimento de aplicações com .NET Digital Innovation One Inc. 8C49368E
- Desenvolvimento básico em Java Digital Innovation One Inc. 1244B20D
- Implementando Collections e Streams com Java Digital Innovation One Inc.

- Introdução ao Framework Spring Boot Digital Innovation One Inc. 6A7545BF
- Desenvolvedor Java Essencial Digital Innovation One Inc. B88FF79A
- Criando aplicações web com Spring Web MVC Digital Innovation One Inc. D059ED3A
- GFT START\_UNI Digital Innovation One Inc. B66FA75D
- Intro to Angular 8 Digital Innovation One Inc. AF7165CE
- Advanced Angular 8 Digital Innovation One Inc. C9C52383
- Angular Frontend Development Desenvolvimento Front-End Angular Digital Innovation One Inc. 5C0ED64F
- Semana OmniStack 11 Rocketseat
- Global Fullstack Developer Digital Innovation One Inc. 071D57E2
- Cloud Computing & Serverless Digital Innovation One Inc. 650D1D54

#### Skills

Python • RESTful WebServices • Software Development • Data Science • Data Analysis • Scrum • React.js • HTML • CSS • DevSecOps